A Guide to the Linda Wilkinson Bock Papers, 1848-1999
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Lind Wilkinson Bock Papers, 1848-1999
The Library of Virginia
42531
7.7 cubic feet
Bock, Linda Wilkinson
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Virginia Heistand Jones of Charles City County, Virginia, 19 January 2006
Biographical Information
Linda Elizabeth Wilkinson was born 9 November 1907 in Surry County, Virginia, to William L. Wilkinson (1861-1957) and Letitia Sarah Deverell Wilkinson (1874-1960), and grew up in Charles City County, Virginia. Linda Wilkinson graduated from Longwood College and became an elementary school teacher. She married Frederic Stanley Bock, Jr., (1909-) 17 July 1933, and they had no children. Linda Wilkinson Bock served as assistant director of the Disability Determination for the Virginia Department of Rehabilitative Services. With her husband, she was active in the Westover Episcopal Church. Bock died 5 March 2005 in Richmond, Virginia, and was buried at Westover Church in Charles City County.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1848-1999, of Linda Wilkinson Bock (1907-2005) of Charles City County and Richmond, Virginia, consisting of papers relating to the Linda and Frederic S. Bock (1909-); Bock and Wilkinson families; William L. Wilkinson (1861-1957); Reverend Charles Edward Stewart (1884-1965) and Eleanor May Deverell Stewart (1883-1971); Westover Church and the Episcopal Church in Virginia; and the history, politics, religious, and social life and customs of Charles City County, Surry County, and Virginia. The collection is organized into the following series: Series I: Linda Wilkinson Bock Papers, 1937-1999. Series II: Wilkinson-Bock Family Papers. Series III: William L. Wilkinson Papers, 1861-1955. Series IV: Account Books, Diaries, Ledgers, 1856-1952. Series V: Stewart Family Papers, 1935-1969. Series VI: Westover Church, 1934-1991. Series VII: Miscellaneous Religious Materials. Series VIII: Pamphlets, Magazines, etc.
Arrangement
Arranged into the following series: Series I: Linda Wilkinson Bock Papers, 1937-1999. Series II: Wilkinson-Bock Family Papers. Series III: William L. Wilkinson Papers, 1861-1955. Series IV: Account Books, Diaries, Ledgers, 1856-1952. Series V: Stewart Family Papers, 1935-1969. Series VI: Westover Church, 1934-1991. Series VII: Miscellaneous Religious Materials. Series VIII: Pamphlets, Magazines, etc.
Contents List
- Linda W. Bock Papers, 1937-1999 (Box 1-2)
  Linda W. Bock Papers, 1937-1999, contain address books, autograph books, books, correspondence, diaries, newsletters, notebooks, notes, pamphlets, and receipts. Diaries, 1942 and 1954-1956, cover Bock's life in Florence, South Carolina, in 1942, and at Byrdwood in Charles City County, Virginia, from 1954 to 1956. Topics include family and personal news; social life and customs; religion, including Bock's family's attendance at Westover Church in Charles City County; World War II; national, state, and local politics, including local elections in Charles City County and the 1956 presidential election; Supreme Court ruling on segregation; Bock's getting a part-time job as a high school counselor; charity giving for 1955 and 1956; and the weather. Also includes bulletins, cards, clippings, and correspondence filed within the diaries. Papers also include an address book; an autograph book, 1937-1938, signed by Bock's seventh grade students at New Kent High School; book of poems and sayings entitled LEAVES OF GOLD given to Bock in 1972; correspondence, 1942 and 1974, to Bock containing family and personal news; newsletter, June 1958, for the Link-Belt Company and newsletter concerning travel allowances; notebook containing a division of personal property, possibly from Byrdwood, 1971, and daily meditations and notes, 1982-1999, of Bock; notes, n.d., for Bock's Westover Church prayer group; pamphlet offering plays for sale to high school drama clubs; and a receipt, 25 May 1962, for Frederic Bock.
  - Linda W. Bock Diary, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Linda W. Bock Diary, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Linda W. Bock Diary, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, cards, etc., from 1942 Bock diary (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, cards, etc. from 1954 Bock diary (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, cards, etc., from 1955 Bock diary (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Linda W. Bock Diary, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Clippings, cards, etc., from 1956 Bock Diary (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Papers, 1942-1974, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Autograph Book, 1937-1938, 7th grade class, New Kent High School (Box 2)
  - Address Book (Box 2)
  - Notebook, 1971, 1982-1989, containing a division of property (1971) and daily meditations (1982-1989) (Box 2)
  - Leaves of Gold given to Linda Bock in 1972 (Box 2)
- Wilkinson-Bock Family Papers (Box 3)
  Wilkinson-Bock family papers consist of Bible records, newspaper clippings, photographs, and miscellaneous items. Bible records consist of records for the Wilkinson and Kimbrough families, and include information on the Bock, Bowman, Branch, Bumpass, Cosby, Deverell, Finney, Jones, Nixon, Stewart, and Thornton families. Clippings, 1916-1988 and no date, include articles on Charles City County and its history; historic houses along the James River, including Berkeley, Shirley, Upper Weyanoke, and Westover; Poplar Hall in Virginia Beach, Virginia; Westover Church in Charles City County; drives through Charles City County; Hanover County, Virginia; the Virginia Episcopal Church; Short Pump, Henrico County, Virginia; United States history; George E. Pickett (1825-1875); William L. Wilkinson; and Philip Lightfoot's dance competition with the devil. Photographs include members of the Wilkinson family, the Branch family, John S. Alvis (1835-1884), equipment and docks of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company, and a Christmas party and a dinner possibly for C and O employees. Miscellaneous items include inscriptions, prayers, notes, and other papers copied or removed from various books.
  - Family Bible records, 1769-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1916-1988, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Wilkinson family photographs (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Railroad and railroad equipment photographs (Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dinner, Christmas party, and gathering photographs (probably Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad employees) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Items removed or copied from various books (Box 3, Folder 6)
- William L. Wilkinson Papers, 1861-1955 (Box 3-5)
  William L. Wilkinson Papers, 1861-1945 contain accounts, agreements, automobile registrations, bills, commissions, contracts, correspondence, deeds, driver's licenses, genealogies, insurance policies, invitations, lists, manifests, marriage license, naturalization papers, oaths, petitions, plats, poems, receipts, summonses, tax records, timetables, and other materials. Topics include Wilkinson's family and social life, his bank account and investments, his accounts with local merchants, his home Byrdwood and his farm property, his service on the county school board, as a notary, and as a justice of the peace, his involvement in the lawsuit of C. H. Wilson et. al. vs. W. J. Thornton, and his taxes; Charles City County history including the Civil War, education, agricultures, and social life and customs; and Surry County, Virginia, history, social life and customs, and Episcopalians including those who attended Ritchie Memorial Church. Papers also include Virginia and local history and politics; dredging in the James River; World War I and Virginia servicemen; the Sons of Confederate Veterans; the Daughters of the American Revolution; Mann Page Lodge No. 157; railroads; and roads and ferries in Charles City and Surry County, Virginia. Series also contains papers of William Fanning Wilkinson (1827-1895) of Charles City County concerning the Civil War and his loyalty oath; Letitia S. Wilkinson's driver's licenses and automobile registrations; William L. Wilkinson's and Letitia Deverell Wilkinson's marriage license; the naturalization paper of Persse Deverell; and accounts of the estate of Thomas Branch (d. 1900).
  - Papers, 1861-1869 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Papers, 1870-1879 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Papers, 1880-1889 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Papers, 1890-1899 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Papers, 1900-June 1901 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Papers, July-December 1901 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Papers, 1902-1909 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Papers, 1910-1917 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Papers, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Papers, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Papers, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Papers, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Papers, 1922-1924 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Papers, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Papers, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Papers, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Papers, 1928-1929 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Papers, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Papers, January-May 1931, (no June or July) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Papers, August-December 1931, (no June or July) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Papers, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Papers, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Papers, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Papers, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Papers, 1940-1946, (no 1945) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Papers, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Papers, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Papers, 1950-1952 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Papers, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Papers, January-April 1954 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Papers, May-September 1954 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Papers, October-December 1954, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Papers, n.d., (correspondence, poems) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Papers, n.d., (miscellaneous papers) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Letitia Wilkinson's driver's licenses, automobile registrations, inspections, and insurance papers, 1927-1945 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Account Books, Diaries, Ledgers, 1856-1952 (Box 6-9)
  Account Books, Diaries, Ledgers, 1856-1952 containing diaries, 1889, 1893-1899, and 1913-1952 (one volume), probably of William L. Wilkinson, concerning crops, weather, and accounts; account books, cash books, payroll books, and ledgers, 1883-1906, for the operation of Sandy Point Farm in Charles City County, owned by Thomas Branch and operated by William F. Wilkinson and William L. Wilkinson; account book, 1880-1881, for operation of Retreat Farm, by William F. Wilkinson; account book, 1865, for operation of Hughes Creek Farm by William F. Wilkinson; account books, 1865-1867, 1870, 1872-1876, 1883, for operations of Woodside Farm by William F. Wilkinson; William F. Wilkinson account book 1868-1878; check stub book, 1889-1904, and receipt book, 1889-1896, of William L. Wilkinson; mill account book, 1884-1906; account book, 1878, of William L. Wilkinson, and account book, 1890-1936, probably of William L. Wilkinson; memorandum book, 1911-1918, of William L. Wilkinson at Tettington, Virginia; account book, 1921, including an account of the battle of Drewry's Bluff; blank yearbook for 1929 given to Edna L. Wilkinson by her grandfather; and account book, 1933-1934, of Frederic S. Bock, including reports and receipts from Spur Distributing Company, Inc.
  - Diary, 1889, [William L. Wilkinson?] (Box 6)
  - Diary, 1893, [William L. Wilkinson?] (Box 6)
  - Diary, 1895, [William L. Wilkinson?] (Box 6)
  - Diary, 1896 [William L. Wilkinson?] (Box 6)
  - Diary, 1897 (1897-1899), [William L. Wilkinson?] (Box 6)
  - Diary, 1913 (1913-1952), [William L. Wilkinson?] (Box 6)
  - Account book, 1880-1881, Retreat Farm, William F. Wilkinson, agent (Box 7)
  - Payroll ledger, 1883-1887, Sandy Point Farm, Thomas Branch, owner (Box 7)
  - Account book, 1884-1886, Thomas Branch, owner, William F. Wilkinson, agent (Box 7)
  - Time book, 1884-1888, Sandy Point Farm (Box 7)
  - Account ledger, 1886-1892, Sandy Point Farm, Thomas Branch, owner, William F. Wilkinson, agent (Box 7)
  - Time book, 1888-1892, Thomas Branch, owner, William L. Wilkinson, clerk (Box 7)
  - Cash book, 1894-1903, Sandy Point Farm, Thomas Branch, owner (Box 7)
  - Cash book, 1904-1906, Thomas Branch estate (Box 7)
  - Hughes Creek daybook, 1865, (William F. Wilkinson) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - [Woodside?] daybook, 186[5?], (William F. Wilkinson) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - [Woodside?] daybook and papers, 1865-1866, 1856-1869, (William F. Wilkinson) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Woodside daybook, 1867, (William F. Wilkinson) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Woodside daybook, 1870, (William F. Wilkinson) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - [Woodside?] daybook, 1872, (William F. Wilkinson) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Woodside daybook, 1873, (William F. Wilkinson) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Woodside daybook, 1874-1875, (William F. Wilkinson) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Woodside daybook, 1876, (William F. Wilkinson) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Woodside daybook, 1883, (William F. Wilkinson) (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Account book, 1868-1878, (William F. Wilkinson) (Box 8)
  - William L. Wilkinson account book, 1878 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Mill account book, 1884-1906, [William L. Wilkinson?] (Box 9)
  - Check stub book, 1889-1904, (William L. Wilkinson) (Box 9)
  - Receipt book, 1889-1896, (William L. Wilkinson) (Box 9)
  - Account book, 1890-1936, [William L. Wilkinson?] (Box 9)
  - Memorandum book, 1911-1918, (William L. Wilkinson) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Minute and dues book, 1919-1924, Sandy Point Civic League (Box 9)
  - Account book, 1921, including an account of the battle of Drewry's Bluff, 1862 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Blank yearbook, 1929 (Box 9)
  - Account book, 1933-1934, (Frederic S. Bock) (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Stewart Family Papers, 1935-1969 (Box 10-12)
  Stewart Family Papers, 1935-1969 consist of diaries, prayer book, and Sunday School lessons of the Stewart Family of Onancock, Accomack County, Kenbridge, Lunenburg County, and Sandston, Henrico County, Virginia. Diaries, 1951-1952, 1956-1960, 1967, and 1969, of Eleanor May Deverell Stewart (1883-1971) record comments on the weather, social life and customs, religion, the Episcopal Church, Episcopalians, and other personal and family information while she and her husband, Reverend Charles E. Stewart (1884-1965), were living in Lunenburg and Henrico Counties, Virginia, and while Reverend Stewart was serving churches in Lunenburg County and Nansemond County, Virginia. She discusses religious services and events at St. Paul's Church, Kenbridge, and St. Andrew's Church, Victoria, both located in Lunenburg County, and at Glebe Church, Driver, and St. John's Church, Chuckatuck, both located in Nansemond County. Prayer book of Reverend Charles E. Stewart contains prayers used by Stewart for various religious holidays, regular services, and particular events. Sunday School lessons, 1935-1938, cover material taught by Eleanor Stewart for kindergarten, and grades 2, 3, and 4, at Holy Trinity Church, in Onancock, Accomack County, Virginia, when Reverend Stewart served that congregation.
  - Eleanor Stewart Diary, 1951 (Box 10)
  - Eleanor Stewart Diary, 1952 (Box 10)
  - Eleanor Stewart Diary, 1956 (Box 10)
  - Eleanor Stewart Diary, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Eleanor Stewart Diary, 1958 (Box 10)
  - Eleanor Stewart Diary, 1959 (Box 11)
  - Eleanor Stewart Diary, 1960 (Box 11)
  - Eleanor Stewart Diary, 1967 (Box 11)
  - Eleanor Stewart Diary, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Reverend Charles E. Stewart prayer book (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Sunday School kindergarten course A, 1935-1936, "The Fatherhood of God"> (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Sunday School kindergarten course B, 1935-1936, "Our Father's Gifts"> (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Sunday School grade 2, 1936-1937, "Obedience to God"> (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Sunday School grade 3, 1936-1938, "God with Man"> (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Sunday School grade 4, 1936-1937, "God's Great Family"> (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Westover Church Papers, 1934-1991 (Box 13-15)
  Westover Church papers, 1934-1991, consist of Westover Church bulletins, 1954-1991; Westover Church newsletters, 1981-1991; Westover Church annual meeting papers, 1958 and 1960; papers, 1934-1986, concerning the day-to-day operations of the church and its financial status; treasurer's reports, 1958-1962; parish account book, 1960; check record, 1954-1963; every member canvass campaigns, 1956-1962; search committee papers, 1974-1975, 1981; members directory, 1982; altar guild manuals; and pamphlet about Westover Church as a historic site.
  - Bulletins, 1954-1991 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, 1991, (through September) (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Annual meetings, 1958, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Papers, 1934-1948 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Papers, 1950-1954 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Papers, January-May 1955 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Papers, June-December 1955 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Papers, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Papers, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Papers, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Papers, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Papers, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Papers, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Papers, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Papers, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Papers, 1964-1966, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Papers, 1974, 1977-1978 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Papers, 1986, 198[?] (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Papers, no date (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1958-1962 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Episcopal parish account book, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Check record, 1954-1959 (1960) (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Check record, 1960-1963 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Every member canvass, 1956-1962 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "Be My Witness" every member visitation packet from the Episcopal Church to Westover Parish (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Search committee, 1974-1975, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Westover Parish directory, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Altar guild manual, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Religious Materials (Box 15-17)
  Miscellaneous Religious Materials. Items include religious magazines: Episcopal Churchnews, The Episcopalian, The Living Church, Virginia Churchman, and The Virginia Episcopalian; Diocese of Virginia parish stewardship manual, 1977; service of holy Eucharist from 182nd Annual Council of the Virginia Diocese, 1977; program for the 191st Annual Council of the Virginia Diocese, 1986; and Virginia Diocese mission outreach-church extension pamphlet. Also Sandy Point Sunday School journal and related papers, 1912-1925; St. James Episcopal Church (Monkton, Maryland) newsletters, 1981-1983; First Presbyterian Church (Hopewell, Virginia) newsletter, December 1981; Ritchie Memorial Episcopal Church (Surry County) 100th anniversary bulletin, 1985; Report of St. James the Less Church (Hanover County), including the by-laws of St. Peter's Church; historic pamphlets on St. Luke's Church (Isle of Wight County, Virginia), and the Episcopal Church in Accomack County; Bruton Parish Church (Williamsburg, Virginia) Christmas bulletin and music program, December 1971; annual congregation meeting, 3 December 1970 of Church of Our Saviour (Sandston, Virginia); Reverend James Alves' installation service, 13 October 1974, as rector of St. Philip's Church (Laurel, Delaware); and papers, 1950 and 1974, of Ginter Park Presbyterian Church (Richmond, Virginia). Also pamphlets and booklets on Episcopal Church teachings, prayer, stewardship, and general religious subjects, as well as miscellaneous papers on religion.
  - Episcopal Churchnews, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - The Episcopalian, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - The Living Church, 1981, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - The Living Church, 1987, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - The Virginia Churchman, 1957, 1962, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - The Virginia Episcopalian, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Diocese of Virginia Parish Stewardship Manual, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - 182nd Annual Council of the Diocese of Virginia service of the Holy Eucharist, 30 January 1977 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Festive celebration of confirmation and installation of the dean, 2 December 1981, Region Nine, Diocese of Virginia (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Program of the 191st Annual Council of the Diocese of Virginia, 30 January-1 February 1986 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Diocese of Virginia missionary outreach-church extension (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Sandy Point Sunday School journal, 1912-1925 (Box 16)
  - Papers, 1912-1925, from Sandy Point Sunday School journal (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1981, St. James Episcopal Church, Monkton, Maryland (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1982, St. James Episcopal Church, Monkton, Maryland (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1983, St. James Episcopal Church, Monkton, Maryland (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter, December 1981, First Presbyterian Church, Hopewell, Virginia (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Bulletin, 1985, Ritchie Memorial Episcopal Church, Surry County, Virginia (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Report of St. James the Less Church, Hanover County, Virginia, including the by-laws of St. Peter's Church (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - The Episcopal Church in Accomack County [Virginia] (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - A Sketch of the "Old Brick Church" Isle of Wight County [St. Luke's Church, Isle of Wight County, Virginia] (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Bruton Parish Church bulletin and program, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Annual meeting, 3 December 1970, Church of Our Saviour, Sandston, Virginia (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Celebration, 13 October 1974, of the new ministry of Reverend James Alves as rector of St. Philip's Episcopal Church, Laurel, Delaware (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Papers, 1948, 1950, Ginter Park Presbyterian Church, Richmond, Virginia (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous churches-items (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Church teachings in the Book of Common Prayer, Reverend Edwin Royall, Christ Episcopal Church, Petersburg, Virginia (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Prayer pamphlets and booklets (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Stewardship pamphlets (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - "Compassionate Friends"--illness and death (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous religious pamphlets (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous church and religious items (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Pamphlets, Magazines, etc. (Box 17)
  Pamphlets, Magazines, etc. Items include 1848 Virginia and North Carolina Almanac; Brandon Lodge, no. 192, Prince George County, Virginia, by-laws; a book of verse, 1889, titled The James River; pamphlets addressing the history of Charles City County, Edmund Ruffin, (1794-1865), John Tyler (1790-1862), and the character of the Confederate soldier; programs for the exercises of the Hanover monument to the Confederate soldier, Edmund Waddell (1855-1931), 300th anniversary of Surry County, the 350th anniversary of Jamestown, and for a play titled The Common Glory;; and the following magazines: Red Cross Courier, 15 August 1929; Anaconda Wire, April 1951; The Spire, March 1952; and Kiplinger Magazine, November 1956. Also includes a report, 1938, on the economic conditions of the South; advance sheets, 1951, of cases before the Virginia Supreme Court of Appeals; miscellaneous pamphlets on Virginia history and driving laws; pageant about Charles City County's history; and other miscellaneous items.
  - Virginia and North Carolina Almanac, 1848 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - By-laws of Brandon Lodge No. 192, Prince George County, Va., 1881 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - The James River or Rhymes, Legendary and Historical, of "the Old Powhatan," 1889 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Charles City: Some of Its Noted Places and People and Personal Recollections of Some of These, 1910, by George L. Christian (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Edmund Ruffin, an Address, 1913, by Lyon G. Tyler (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - The Character and Services of the Confederate Soldier "in War and Peace:" an Address, 1914 [1913], by Captain John Lamb (Box 17, Folder 10)